# Mansee Agrawal

# Machine Learning Engineer

J +918109423050 ▼ mansiagrawaljec@gmail.com 🛅 LinkedIn 🗘 GitHub 😩 Portfolio 🌗 HuggingFace

# Summary

Machine Learning Engineer with 4+ years of experience in building and deploying AI/ML solutions. Proficient in Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, Generative AI and Computer Vision. Strong background in Python, Transformers, and full-stack model deployment using Flask and FastAPI. Experienced in both research and production environments with a passion for solving real-world problems.

# Education

# Technocrats Institute of Technology Excellence

Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh

Master of Engineering in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning

2020-2022

# Jabalpur Engineering College

Jabalpur, Madhya Pradesh

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

2016-2020

# Professional Experience

#### Iopex Technologies Bangalore

# Machine Learning Engineer

03/2024 - present

- Working on Deep Learning, NLP, Generative AI, Chatbots, RAG, LLMs (LLaMa 3.2, LLaMa-Vision, GPT-4), Layout LM, and text-clustering
- Build and fine-tuned RAG pipelines using Langchain, hybrid search, reranking, chunking strategies.
- Finetuned LayoutLM for extracting structured data from order forms.

Justdial Bangalore

### Machine Learning Engineer

05/2022 - 03/2024

- Developed and fine-tuned models for object detection, image classification (CNN, Yolo, ResNet50, EfficientNetV2, Swin, ViT), OCR (PaddleOCR), and NLP tasks.
- Implemented LLM-based applications using Transformers (BERT, GPT, LLaMA), and deployed solutions with Flask/FastAPI.
- Experience with Kafka, RabbitMQ, Docker, and vector databases (Milvus, Weaviate).

Kloudspot Bangalore

# Machine Learning Engineer

10/2020 - 05/2022

- Developed CV applications for image/video processing, including detection/classification models (YOLO, SSD,
- Built and deployed autoencoders for facial reconstruction.
- Converted models to OpenVINO, TensorRT, and TFLite for efficient deployment.

# **Projects**

# Chatbot with RAG Pipeline – Generative AI for Licensing Queries

- Retrieved relevant documents from Mongo Atlas using LangChain.
- Used GPT-4 with context-based summarization to generate user responses.

## Image Classification & Object Detection

- Trained CNN, ResNet, EfficientNet, Swin Transformer, and ViT for tasks like mask detection, age classification, blur/clean classification and orientation detection.
- Built autoencoders for face reconstruction.
- Used Python, Transformers, Keras, PyTorch, Flask, Fast API.

# Natural Language Processing

- Done post processing like POS tagging, NER, sentiment analysis on text extracted from images using PaddleOCR and on raw text as well.
- Fine-tuned LayoutLM for form extraction and DONUT for banner text extraction.
- Built sentiment and NLI models to identify contradictions from review pros and cons.
- Developed DistilBERT-based QA model for key info extraction from reviews.
- Worked on Llama, Langchain to generate the reviews.

# Technical Skills

Languages: Python

Frameworks/Tools: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, Transformers, LangChain, Flask, FastAPI, Docker, Kafka, RabbitMQ,

Git

Domains: Computer Vision, NLP, OCR, Generative AI

Techniques: CNNs (ResNet, EfficientNet), Transformers (BERT, GPT, LLaMA, T5), RNNs (LSTM, GRU), LayoutLM, DONUT, YOLO, SSD

# Achievements

- Awarded Top Talent (FY 23-24) for outstanding performance
- Winner, Smart India Hackathon (2019 & 2020)
- GATE Qualified (2020)

## Interests

- Dancing
- Badminton
- travelling